Suma, Yusoph G.

Email: yusophh@gmail.com **Portfolio:** yusoph-dev.github.io

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yusoph-dev/

Github: https://github.com/yusoph-dev

Profile:Experienced Full Stack Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in content management systems (such as Wordpress, Shopify), Laravel, Codelgniter, Full-Stack Development, and Computer Hardware Troubleshooting. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor's degree focused in Computer Science from Taguig City University.

Industry Knowledge

- Web Development
- Search Engine Optimization
- PC Troubleshooting
- Web Services
- Programming
- Web Design
- Web Deployment
- SEO Optimization

Skills (Technologies, Tools, Etc.)

- Wordpress
- HTML5
- CSS3/SASS
- SASS
- JAVASCRIPT (ES6)
- JQUERY
- CodeIgniter
- Laravel
- Vue JS
- React
- Bootstrap
- Prestashop
- VS Code
- Atom IDE
- Responsive UI
- Basecamp
- Trello
- Slack
- Windows/Mac OS
- Gsuit

Area of Expertise

- Testing & Troubleshooting (Debugging)
- Project Management
- Effective Communication
- Teamwork
- Strategic Planning
- Solutions & Engineering
- Agile Development
- Reverse Engineering
- Google Webmaster
- Github, GitLab (for code versioning tool)
- Gitkraken (Git Gui)
- PHP (Programming Language)
- Sql (Database)
- Mysql
- Visual Basic
- Java
- C++
- Joomla
- Google Web Master Tools
- Google Api's
- Cpanel
- Figma
- Adobe XD
- Postman
- Fork
- TablePlus
- VS Code

Education

2013-2017 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Taguig City University

Employment History

05/2021 – Current Full Stack Web Developer Hiraya Mnl.

- Create NFT generators for client SNKRHUD, tech used is Node, Python, Github.
- Create e-Commerce website thru shopify for client TOQA, tech used is Shopify (liquid), Github, Figma, Adobe XD, Jquery.
- Create Frontend UI for client SERVD, tech used is VueJS and Github.
- Developed NFT UI & Functionality for flowscorenft.com

Responsibilities:

- Involved and participate in the overall application lifecycle
- · Main focus on coding and debugging
- Conduct UI tests and optimize performance Collaborate with multidisciplinary team of designers, developers and system administrators
- Recording data and reporting it to proper parties, such as clients or leadership.
- Design and implementation of data storage solutions
- Create servers and databases for functionality.
- Learn about new and emerging technologies
- Ensuring responsiveness of applications
- Taking lead on projects, as needed.

05/2021 – 11/2021 Full Stack Web Developer Philippine Chamber of Commerce and Industry (PCCI)

- Create UI/UX for portals of PCCI-CO and CCG, tech used is Node, VueJS, Laravel, Mysql, Github, Aws S3 and adobe XD.
- Responsible developing, testing, improving and maintaining new and existing databases to assist users
 retrieve data and report effectively. Will collaborate with users to provide technical support and identify new
 requirements. Ensures database systems run effectively and securely on a daily basis.

Responsibilities:

- Design stable, reliable and effective database
- Optimize and maintain legacy systems
- Modify databases according to the requirements and perform tests
- Solve database usage issues and malfunctions Identify user requirements and new features
- Develop technical and training manuals
- Provide data management support to users
- Ensure all database programs meet company and performance requirements
- Research and suggest new database technology, services, systems and protocols

04/2018 – 05/2021 Full Stack Web Developer OrangeApps Inc.

- Create and replicated CMS (Content Management System) websites using WordPress(Elementor) for clients <u>Holy Family Parochial School</u>, <u>Immaculate Conception Cathedral School</u>, <u>St. Joseph Catholic School</u>.
- Create from scratch the SIS (Student Information System) platform for client World Citi Colleges with 3 campuses. It includes the functionalities which I created/enhanced: Student Admission form, Enrollment Dashboard, Audit Trailing, Cashiering (Create transactions, View customer current outstanding balances, Manage checks, Create account payment adjustments, Create (Tuition, Collection, Adjustment, Checks,

- Voided, Reservation Reports.), Void customer Transactions). Also I enhanced the admission mobile design responsiveness.
- Create from the scratch the Content Management System for client <u>OB Montessori</u>, it provides a simple access for the Administrator and students on their school store with access to required supplies and uniforms. The admin can view/manage the orders of the customers using their admin accounts.
- Worked in the School platform team of <u>Magsaysay Center for Hospitality and Culinary Arts (MIHCA)</u> to create modules like setup Courses Tuition Fees, School Course Schedule Management, Shifting module (module for shifting courses per student), Enrolment, Managing of Student Master list, Managing of Certificates for graduated Students, Cashiering Module which includes (Bank Payment, Audit Trail, Tuition Adjustments), Reports Module which includes (Collection, Voided, Adjustment and Receivables).
- Create another module for Documents in the school <u>Manila Waldorf</u> which includes displaying of Students Grading Activities.
- Maintain and develop the website of Deped Makati.

06/2017 – 04/2018 Backend Web Developer OrangeApps Inc.

- Develop and maintain every client's School Websites basic functionalities.
- Create a new module called Documents for their basic functionality, it is a module that manages Documents uploaded by users.
- Ensure software stability via regression, support quality assurance, and perform unit and user-acceptance testing to identify bugs and ensure production operations run successfully.
- Work quickly and carefully to complete small edits requested by customers, develop plans for completing larger projects, collaborate with colleagues, and suggest new solutions to improve existing websites.
- Perform UI designs and coding, creating reusable objects and templates, wireframes for web pages and email templates; manage maintenance, updates, expansions, and scaling of each design.
- Perform regular file backups to local directories for recovery.

01/2017 – 04/2017 Backend Web Developer – Intern OrangeApps Inc.

- Learn the process on how to work in an actual project in web development.
- Provide ideas and processes for enhancing the E-Learning Module.
- Worked on bug fixes and Quality assurance for the given task by the company for each of their developed school websites.

Honors & Awards

- Best Thesis on System fair competition held at Taguig City University
 Dec 2016 honor issued at Taguig City University Computer Science Department
- Champion at First Forest Hackathon
 Sept. 2016 honor issued at University of the Philippines Los Banos.
- 2nd Runner Up at Web Design Competition in University of Makati's 5th I.T Olympics
 Aug 2015 honor issued at University of Makati